Finding aid for Smith Club of Seattle Records CA.MS.00329
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Seattle records
1912-2003
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Seattle
CA.MS.00329
1.458 linear feet (4 containers)
The Smith Club of Seattle records contains minutes, notebooks, correspondence, and mailings documenting the club's activities.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Club of Seattle was formed in January, 1912. The earliest records list a variety of activities including social events, meetings, lectures, and collaborations with alumnae from other Seven Sister colleges in the area.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection consists of club notebooks from 1968-1989. These notebooks include club correspondence, fundraising materials, agendas and minutes. The collection also contains the Club President's files from the 1970s and early 1980s, which hold correspondence and notes. Additionally, there are board minutes from the 1940s through the 1980s. The general files include a club scrapbook from 1912-19 which contains clippings about the Smith College Unit in Grecourt, France, during World War I, a file about Smith WEST, a publicity trip taken by President Mendenhall in 1974 to visit several cities on the West Coast, including Seattle, information on membership and fundraising, and newsletters. The general files also hold correspondence with and material from the Alumnae Association and materials on Seven Sisters conferences.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith Club of Seattle Records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1939-55 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1956-75 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1976-82 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1985-86 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes: Planning Session and Retreat, 1997 (Box 1)
- Board Members, 1983-86 (Box 1)
- Board Position Descriptions, 1983-86 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1973-74 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1977-79 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1981-83 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1985-86 (Box 1)
- Vice-President's File, 1973-74 (Box 1)
- Secretary's File, 1973-74 (Box 2)
- Treasurer's File, 1973-74 (Box 2)
- Treasurer's File, 1983-85 (Box 2)
- Treasurer's File, 1985-86 (Box 2)
- Hospitality Chairman, 1973-74 (Box 2)
- Publicity Chairman, 1973-74 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1965-70 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1963-70 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1971-72 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1975-76 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1977-81 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1986-87 (Box 2)
- Club Notebook, 1987-89 (Box 2)
- Alumnae Council, 1983-86; undated (Box 3)
- Alumnae Fund, 1973-74; 1985 (Box 3)
- Alumnae Trustee and Medal Nominations, 1973-74 (Box 3)
- Annual Reports, 1978-79 (Box 3)
- Annual Reports, 1984 (Box 3)
- Book Award, 1986 (Box 3)
- Candidate's Committee, 1973-74; 1985-86 (Box 3)
- Clippings, 1961-68 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Scholarship Recipients, 1967; 1971 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Smith College, 1985-86 (Box 3)
- Dinner Party for Jill Ker Conway, 1975 (Box 3)
- Events, 1960-85 (Box 3)
- Fundraising, 1962-2001; undated (Box 3)
- Members - Dorothy Arnold, 1997 (Box 3)
- Membership, 1968-89 (Box 3)
- Newsletter, 1956-78 (Box 3)
- Newsletter, 1983-86 (Box 3)
- Newsletter, 1996-2003 (Box 3)
- Photographs, 1972 (Box 4)
- Program Evaluations, 1985-86 (Box 4)
- Scrapbook, 1912-19 (Box 4)
- Seven College Conference, 1960-74 (Box 4)
- Smith WEST, 1974 (Box 4)
- Women's College Clubs - Co-run events, 1983-86 (Box 4)